those people in the YouTube comments
that read the chromium source code they
the real MVPs man like that's the real
[__] yeah just leave that in a YouTube
comment instead of like it or something
dude I like one like you know it's crazy
[Music]
thank you yo yo yo how's it going dude
you look like you just got hit by a
train
dude I'm so tired
for contacts yeah I'll give a little
context here I did two Live Hack events
back to back uh one week and then the
other week so
two weeks ago I was in London with you
we did uh the hacker One Life hacking
event yeah Dr Cosman then I went right
from there I flew to Seoul South Korea
oh my gosh and I was there for another
week and I did uh a meta live hacking
event
um and I participated with nagley former
uh podcast guest and uh you know he
found some really cool bugs on there and
uh then yesterday I flew home so I am
like my body is screaming at me about
time zones and all that stuff uh Seoul
is 16 hours ahead of here and London is
eight hours ahead of here so it was just
from like one eight hour time difference
into another eight hour time difference
and then back to my normal time so I'm
uh I'm I'm like half asleep right now so
you'll have to forgive uh any latency
that I've got in my brain yeah no
worries man I'm sorry I picked such a
tricky episode to prep for uh for when
you come back but yeah I haven't I
haven't seen you this tired looking in a
long time
um but yeah I mean I was I was gonna ask
you because we haven't really had the
chance to catch up either how was the
how was The Meta event dude yeah the med
event was really cool uh we found a zero
day I think that's all I can say uh we
found a zero day in an open source piece
of software
um and it ended up in an xss I think
that's that's about as much as I would
say that's big on Facebook man they pay
big for those yeah yeah it was a pretty
cool pretty cool bug uh I was actually
very surprised that we were able to find
it uh a lot of the people that I talked
to there who are like big time Facebook
hackers were also quite surprised they
said that the Nexus has on Facebook
especially Facebook core is something
that really yeah uh it's like a once a
year type of thing it really almost
never happens so I was I was pretty
stoked that we found that and that it
worked and then it popped and all that
yeah pretty quick too I think I saw like
the I think I saw nogly flexing in a
hacker chat like like two or three days
into the event and I was like oh [__]
yeah yeah so shout out to space raccoons
basically we also collabed with uh that
event and space raccoon had exploited
very similar
uh probably within the last year
um he exploited a very very similar bug
to this and so when we added him to the
group we were just talking about like
the leads and stuff that we were looking
at and all that kind of stuff and I
mentioned I was like yeah we have this
uh we have this potential like zero day
but I've been looking at it I haven't
really uh gone into like the full
details on how to exploit it and he was
like oh I'm pretty sure I know how to
exploit this and in like an hour he
popped it and I was like Ah that's
amazing so that's like the whole like I
mean that's like a perfect example of
collaboration and how like you can merge
like past experience together by like
working with other hackers because I I'm
sure we could have exploited it but it
would have taken us significantly more
time and you know it was just so much
easier to bring somebody in who knew
what they were doing and yeah for sure
man space raccoon is also a uh previous
podcast guest he was I think I think he
was the first guest we had I believe he
was yeah yeah so definitely we'll we'll
link those episodes down in the
description
um both knogly and Space Racer [__]
Supreme hackers yeah yeah how is how are
the Vibes like you know we've done a lot
of hacker one live hacking events
together you know and I feel like hacker
one's got it down pat pretty well now
but how are the meta live hockey event
vibes
yeah so I think it's important to
remember that meta
run well meta runs their own Bugatti
program yeah and meta also isn't a bug
Bounty company so for hacker one the
live hacking events are both a marketing
opportunity as well as something that is
core to their brand right for meta it's
a security event you know I mean it's
like a meet-up so for meta you know the
the swag and stuff is significantly like
less over the top like all the ceremony
and stuff is significantly less over the
top and all that kind of stuff because
all they really care about is like
finding cool bugs paying for those bugs
and having people on site and like
you're showing them a good time and for
hacker one it's like how do we make this
like amazing hacking event experience
right and so like I think it's two two
very different things but overall like
the core of the event in terms of like
having hackers on site being able to
like talk with all these like amazing
people I got to talk with
um like Yusuf who's like an amazing
Facebook hacker actually focuses only on
on meta and that kind of stuff and a lot
of the people there are people who like
dedicate all their time to hacking on
meta which is something that I barely
spend any time hacking on so it was like
a very interesting like perspective
shift to get to talk to those people and
see like how they approach a platform
like meta and the types of stuff that
they find and all that kind of stuff and
it was really really impressive to see
that the bugs that people found so nice
dude wow not gonna lie man not gonna lie
I'm a little jealous it sounded like an
awesome event I um I had a bachelor
party that weekend which was also
awesome but nice you know South Korea
live hacking event sounds pretty
freaking lit man yeah it's always a very
cool place I'd never been to South Korea
so though
right yeah yeah we took uh we did a day
or two ahead and a day or two after as
well just to like get to see sites and
explore and go shopping and experience
the the country in the city so uh yeah I
definitely would recommend going to
South Korea it's it's an amazing place
and you should experience it for
yourself nice man well Joel you're
you're six minutes in you're still alive
so I hope we won't fall asleep as we
talk about all the mega technical stuff
we're gonna talk about today because
unlike some of the past episodes that
we've had
um this one is gonna be like pretty in
the freaking weeds so
um yeah yeah I was just mentioning I I
send you a message like five minutes
before we started that this whole
episode could be a news episode because
of the amount of like news and links and
new very relevant stuff that's happened
in the last like week or two
um around this topic being you know like
browser quirks and behaviors and yeah
restrictions and that kind of stuff yeah
yeah there's been a bunch and uh and
yeah I I messaged Joel and I was like
hey man you might want to like you know
allocate a little extra prep time for
this episode and I'm sure he was like
you know laying in bed trying to get
every last little bit of sleep but I was
like literally adding stuff to this
episode up until the last minute so
sorry if you didn't get a chance to
review all of it I I you know there's
some Grace I know you're coming right
back from the from the life hacking
event so
um yeah I guess we'll just kind of hop
into it um the first one that I want to
talk about I don't know if you saw this
one but
um it's titled hunting so new stuff
right this is uh hunting for nginx alias
traversals in the wild this was released
just yesterday
um by I don't know how to print like I
want to pronounce this Hawkeye Labs but
I'm not sure if that's exactly how you
pronounce it
um but dude this is just such a
beautiful example of like taking
research and then applying it and just
popping crazy bugs right like this this
research has been out here this nginx
research was released by Orange in black
hat 2018. this is five-year-old research
right and then you know if you read
through the blog post homies just like
okay well let's apply this so he goes to
GitHub search and just writes a regex
and then pops like multiple bounties
with it and I'm just like what a g
yeah yeah so I was talking with with
nagley a lot we were hanging a lot out a
lot well on on this whole trip and I
think
this is like a perfect use case for
nuclei right where yeah like this is
probably something that doesn't exist in
a rule already maybe it does right but I
mean if it did it probably would have
been found by more things yeah but
if you see research like this like some
like if you were to have noticed like
oranges blog post back in 2018 or their
presentation back in 2018. yeah that
would be a great use case for something
that you can get an advantage on or an
edge against everybody else by turning
that into a quarry putting it into your
own nuclei setup and then running it
across all the targets that you're
monitoring and then using that to your
advantage as sort of you know nobody
like it's out there but it's not out
there you know what I mean yeah no for
sure and and I I think that's true and I
think there's I I've actually personally
done some scanning for this for this
exact vulnerability
um but I think what's really interesting
about the way that this guy you know
applied it was he you know went after
open source stuff
with this um which I think is really
smart because by nature of this um
and I know we we actually haven't said
which which research we're talking about
this is the uh uh off by off by a slash
research
um by uh by Orange in 2018 so
essentially if you have a nginx location
defined and the location does not have a
slash at the end and then the Alias that
it's pointing to or the or the um I
think there's one other one
well yeah the Alias that it's pointing
to does not have a slash at the end
um you can actually res it can actually
result in a path traversal uh I think
it's the other way actually it has so oh
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah so the
location doesn't have a slash but the
Alias does have a slash and then that
makes it vulnerable the location
does have
wait hold on hold on hold on hold on
hold on so so it says for the technique
to be applicable the following
conditions must be met the location
directive should not have a trailing
slash in its path and an alias directive
must be present with the location
context and it must end with a slash
right right because that slash is what's
getting passed through
right okay gotcha okay yeah so um and
then thanks for clearing that up man I
love how like your brain operating at 50
still like you know no um at least I can
still read it yeah I got that going for
me you got that one on me Joel
um no yeah so uh and and like I said
before I'd actually played around with
this specific phone and I wrote my own
sort of um nuclei module for this it's
not nuclei it was my own custom thing
but um I think the open source approach
is really really smart because
um by nature of this vulnerability you
only have one path to Russell right you
only get to go up one directory level
and so you kind of gotta know what is in
that directory in order to be able to
fully exploit this vulnerability and so
um in the in the
in the blog post he talks about
um exploiting this against bit Warden uh
self-hosted bit Warden and uh and it
resulting in the database
um being leaked uh which is like a big L
yeah yeah bit one's a password manager
right yeah yeah so yeah that's great and
he said that they they um fixed the
issue and give it the max Bounty for the
broke Bounty program so love to see that
and then I think they also found
something similar on Google
um
seems like that one got a little bit
less rewarded but um it it definitely
seems like yeah it's only 500 bucks for
that it seems like that should have a
bit more but maybe there were some
mitigating factors but yeah
I'm sure that that there were I feel
like uh and this is a little little bit
of a tangent but having looked at like
the Facebook and Microsoft and Google
programs a little bit now yeah it's
really crazy how much money they pay I
mean we're talking like for perspective
here
Zoom probably the second most high
paying program would be my guess on
hacker one probably program they paid I
think like seven or eight million total
number one I think they paid 14 12 or 14
million Google and Facebook and
Microsoft I believe all paid at least
one million dollars last year alone
wow
dang dude and that's without running
Live Events
wow that's some serious that's some
serious output yeah it's I mean it's
it's kind of crazy
um and I think part of that is that like
some of the bugs they pay for are very
very high bugs so I know like Google had
this one bug that they paid like
over a half a million for it was like a
really bad pixel bug
um wow and like you know
some of the hackers at the Facebook
event for example like Yusuf he walked
away with like a couple hundred K by
himself so he posted on Twitter yeah
yeah so like definitely there are some
like high earners and stuff and some
some categories but I think it's
important to realize that even like some
of the largest programs on hacker one
are kind of dwarfed by these Mega
companies who are doing their own
programs
and uh yeah I mean it's it's really wild
like generally speaking like if they're
paying low it's because it's like
there's some like crazy crazy
confounding Factor because they're
pretty they're pretty liquid and they
like to play bounties pretty pretty
liquid I like that I always I look for
the programs that are really liquid if
you know yeah yeah
so um but yeah I just wanted to
highlight this one because I thought
this was a really cool application and
just encouraging that like you can go
find old research that you know has been
around for a while and you know go and
apply it write your own tool write your
own way to look come up with your own
way to look for it and uh it'll it could
result in some really cool bugs yeah
well I also like that
uh in this blog like the first thing
that they tried was just using a GitHub
code search which is a super accessible
way to search for stuff because it's
open it's free it's available you can
just literally go to cs.github.com and
yeah you know go ahead and and search
for your regex that's gonna find the
vulnerabilities and make you money right
out of the bat that you don't even have
to spin up a special tool or anything
like that so and does code search I know
that they just pushed this out not too
long ago I can't guess I can't say just
recently does it have 100 indexing now
or no that I'm not sure about I know
that it was limited in the beginning
yeah I think they probably expanded it
all the way now yeah but Source graph
which is like probably the the main
competitor or I guess code search is
probably the competitor to Source graph
because sourcecraft kit was there first
but uh sourcecraft you could always spin
up your own source graph instance as
well and then you can tell it to index
you know a bunch of repos or you can
tell it to index like I don't think you
can have it indexed like all of GitHub
yeah that would be pretty insane yeah
but if you have like a list of
organizations right so if you take a
list of public bug bending programs go
get their GitHub organization names put
them in a list index all of their repos
that would probably be a good strategy
yeah no totally agree there
um next on the list is this another
Banger from Port swinger research I have
to say I really appreciate that account
man like that's they've really put out
some good stuff
um and this the tweet that I'm talking
about is the one regarding
um popovers uh which is a new feature in
Chrome and you know just as they as
Chrome releases it portswicker research
finds a way to pop something with it
um and essentially there's a new way to
trigger xss on uh any any
um I think it's any element yeah any tag
yeah that's what I was I was trying to
come up with arbitrary yeah or any
arbitrary it doesn't even have to be an
element right it's just any tag yeah
yeah so um that's really cool to see and
then it was also really cool to see the
surrounding research on that too that
kind of everyone like tier 53 commented
on it
um I don't know how to pronounce this
guy's name erstol erstel commented on it
yeah uh sort of brain boggling stuff
um so yeah that's definitely a cool
technique to be on the lookout for I'm
not sure how often like this will be
useful as opposed to a different
exercise Vector maybe like helpful for
bypassing some laughs and stuff like
that but um still something cool to be
aware of nonetheless
yeah so I when I was looking at it I
think it it's like at minimum
one click right or two clicks yeah so
there's definitely some some confounding
factors here that it's going to lower
the impact a little bit depending on how
the company looks at it like some
companies might just say any xss is
valuable to us even if it's too quick
maybe you can also craft a POC that
would make it plausible kind of like a
click jacking type of thing where you
can you know create a scenario that
would make sense for the user to be
clicking twice or something like that
um but even still I I I think like
over the last couple months we've seen a
lot of things get removed from chrome
and a lot of uh changes that have made
things more secure and it's been almost
almost disheartening as a bug Bounty
Hunter to see that all these xss vectors
disappear and uh they look it out for us
they're they're adding new xss vectors
for us it's nice yeah
becoming more vulnerable just what I
thought that I was gonna have to stop
filing these bugs now there are new
methods here we go yeah yeah so um and I
think it's also really cool that it
triggers a sort of a multi-element sort
of thing right because there's like the
button that you click on and then
there's this custom attribute pop over
Target and then you provide the ID for a
different element and then it triggers
something on that element and as cure53
pointed out that element can even be
hidden or
um disabled right disabled yeah yeah
which I think is is really cool as well
because there are some Fringe
circumstances and you we really get down
in the weeds um you know with some of
these technicalities sometimes but when
you have all these things floating
around in your head as you see these
scenarios pop up uh over time when
you're hunting
um it's really it's really great when
you can use some really Fringe research
to pop a bug and that's how you avoid
dupes as well because not a lot of
people are on top of this stuff
yeah you know the first thing that
popped into my mind about the hidden
value thing is a pattern that I see a
lot in what in web which is that
there'll be either like a state or maybe
a token or something in the URL
parameters and that'll get reflected
into an HTML form yeah for like
submission like it'll be like a token
and then you'll click a button in the
page and it'll submit that value again
yeah and I think if you could find
obviously you need kind of a second
injection point to make it so that you
can trigger the the popover Target but
if you can inject this even into a
hidden form element right then you can
take advantage of that excess yeah yeah
for sure and that's a good that's a good
exercise tip in general is that and you
can even work backwards from it right
like if you're trying to figure out what
queer parameters could go into uh you
know could be used in this specific page
you can go into the source look at the
hidden input parameters right and and
see what the name or ID of those are and
then try those in the URL and that may
allow you to set some malicious defaults
um by a URL parameter if it's reflected
down in there or might even allow you to
get xss so yeah yeah for sure so
definitely check out like the quote
tweets and stuff on that Port swinger
research and yeah also just set your
Tweet alerts up for reports with your
research because I don't think there's
ever been a tweet that they've made
that's been like ah this is not a good
tweet but like I feel like every time
every single thing that they push out is
is very like high quality research just
generally speaking we've also talked
about the portswicker Web Academy and
stuff is also really high quality yeah
it's always like very on the front edge
of like what's actually exploitable and
all that kind of stuff and and good for
for training and getting new people like
accustomed to exporting xss and other
web web vulnerabilities so
um definitely go check that that out
check out their account and their
website for sure
um okay so before we move on from this
section check out the Tweet by saroosh
um or still
this is really this is really
interesting to me I was like kind of
looking at this for a while before I
could figure out what the heck was going
on here and it this is not even really
like anything crazy to do with the
popover Target thing the thing that's
really crazy for me with this is that he
uses two equal signs after pop over
Target right so the the code we're
talking about here is is button space
popover Target equals equals and then
it's a double quote right so he's
defining an attribute but this attribute
is not using the double quote as the
beginning of the attribute like you
would normally see in HTML it's actually
using two equal signs so the first equal
sign defines the attribute and the
second equal sign is just a content of
the attribute right yeah and then that
inside of that content of the attribute
is a double quote right yeah I think
this is really really Nifty and I think
you can use this in a bunch of different
situations for WAAF bypasses or X's test
filter bypasses because
um I imagine that there will be a regex
that is looking specifically when it's
parsing HTML attributes looking
specifically for that for that um for
that equal sign and then double quote
right so if you have two equal signs
that might continue the regex and it
will assume that the double quote is the
beginning of the attribute but actually
the the second equal sign is the
beginning of the attribute which I think
I think that was really cool I hadn't
seen that technique before yeah I didn't
I didn't really realize like this was
possible and yeah reading it it's very
confusing to understand like what's
actually going on here it I am I correct
that it's using the equals as the Val
like the value of the attribute so like
basically your popover Target is
something that's called like equals
yeah yeah it looks like it yeah and so
you see look at the ID down there it's a
so if you look at input right the input
tag the ID for that is equals equals
equals you know uh less than bang dash
dash right and that matches the pop-over
target from above which looks like an
HTML comment to a parser but actually
this is this is just a part of the the
attribute because of the way it's set up
so really really cool
um stuff there and I think
cross-applicable in a lot of other xss
scenarios yeah I have a feeling this
will probably come up with uh some some
like third-party access or HTML parsers
and stuff that are going to be checking
for xss by parsing the HTML elements
just like you said and uh we'll be
handling that incorrectly because it's
going to look like an HTML comment in
there or something like that or might
not one to one meet the spec and they
might just like
have like a one character slip up and
that's all it takes yeah for sure so
definitely this one's a little bit
easier to to see than to hear about so
definitely check out this one we'll link
it in the description
yeah
um all right so speaking of cool xss
stuff
um we have another one here which was
kind of surprising to me
um uh the rce man ironically had a
client side bug
um uh tweeted this out and he said don't
forget about the magical math element
which can make any HTML element
clickable within the Firefox browser and
so he defines a math element and then
inside of that defines an xss tag just a
you know less than xss space you know
defines that tag and and uh sets the
href to that to a JavaScript href and
you click on that and it triggers in in
Firefox which and I tried to figure out
why this is like what is it about the
math tag that makes it makes everything
clickable and I couldn't figure it out
so it it seems like this is just one of
those weird quirks it might help to know
in some written circumstances yeah it's
it's super super weird
um and I we'll add a little caveat here
um Firefox I think like in Tech a lot of
people use Firefox and like it's it's an
easy misconception to think of Firefox
is probably one of the largest browsers
out there however if you look up the
browser market share stats the top right
hold on hold on let me guess
I want to say it's like I want to say
it's around 12 percent
12 Firefox yeah I I don't I don't know
not even close what really not even
close yeah not even close okay so it's
like 60 Chrome right 20 to 25 Safari and
Firefox is at about two and a half
percent no way really it's yeah it's
underneath Edge right so like Edge yeah
oh my God under Edge so like the reality
is that like the majority of people who
are using a computer are using the
built-in browser or or Chrome just
because of its dominance in the market
so like Chrome obviously number one by a
long shot but then it's Safari and Edge
as the two next browsers because those
are the ones that are built into Mac and
windows
wow dude that is definitely surprising
to me and I will say though um I feel
like Edge is gonna gained some
popularity back because you can only use
Bing like search AI stuff in Edge I
tried to do it in Chrome the other day
and it was like no no no no go to Edge
and I'm like that's true
I launched the edge like for the first
time in probably five years because I
wanted to use the Bing AI to search for
something exactly man so I don't know I
I you know Microsoft is really leaning
into trying to claw back some of that
you know browser real estate
um but I don't know and this may I mean
I wouldn't be surprised if this pulled a
percent or two away from them and at the
end of the day it is using chromium you
know as a base now so
you know may not be too bad who knows
yeah it might not be I think like the
biggest thing is just like how
integrated Chrome is with yeah your
accounts and just extensions and all
that kind of stuff
yeah yeah for sure man
um dude we just have so much xss stuff
too so many weird yeah yeah we I feel
like HTML parsers are really taking a
beating this week yeah
um so the next one that's on the list
and I linked a YouTube video in the
notes like a genius
um but this is this is uh the Youtube
video is live overflows
um summary and we'll link this in the
description of course is live overflows
um summary of some research that he he
did based off of a weird tweet he saw
and I've actually seen him do this a
couple times where he like sees some
weird tweet and he's like oh that's kind
of odd I bet that has security
implications and then he like creates a
video of him like sussing that out and I
think that's gold right like if anybody
is trying to you know this isn't a
particularly beginners oriented podcast
but if there are you know beginners out
there trying to learn how to you know up
your research game that is a great
example of of what to do and what the
pros do when when when trying to you
know conduct some security research so
definitely check out live overflow's
video in this one he's talking about a
tweet that he saw where it said there's
something weird about the
um less than and then number uh tags
right because numbers aren't valid HTML
tags and somehow
um the first so if you have an open tag
it gets HTML encoded because it's not a
valid thing but if you have a closed tag
it gets stuck inside of a comment
right right so it's like yeah this is
kind of weird
um so he kind of goes through there and
comes up with this way to like this this
theory that he's got that this is going
to bypass a bunch of HTML sanitizers and
then he goes and puts them into HTML
sanitizers and nah you know people have
known about this for a long time
um but it was a really cool exercise in
how to research some quirky Behavior so
I figured I'd give it a shout out anyway
yeah yeah and Lupine uh had a follow-up
about
you know about this this weird behavior
um and they were talking about
in a video that this might be an
interesting way to bypass a wife and
then somebody that left a comment
linking to the source code in the
chromium engine like where this parsing
actually happens and like what what it's
looking for in terms of like a comment
tag and it was super super interesting
to see
you know the kind of quirks that you can
do because of this sort of edge case
Behavior where it's like a closing tag
with a number in it that gets then
converted into something else yeah yeah
for sure man I love the you know those
people in the YouTube comments that read
the chromium source code they the real
MVPs man like that's the real [__] yeah
just leave that in a YouTube comment
instead of like yeah dude got one like
you know it's crazy legendary like what
an absolute Legend right
um so yeah like you said really awesome
stuff there I actually double clicked
into the uh the Google Chromium um
source code and yeah it was really cool
about and this is the comment
specifically was it wasn't about the um
the numbers like I was talking about
before this was about the question mark
um and so if you put a question mark in
so you do less than sign question mark
right this is no HTML encoding here this
is just raw you know no entities or
anything
um then that actually gets converted
into it comment which I thought was
really interesting and I in a little bit
later in the episode today if we don't
talk or you know talk to the end of the
episode about new stuff I'm going to
talk about um some other cool ways to do
job comments in JavaScript but um this
is a really interesting one that uh kind
of like I didn't I didn't realize you
could trigger an HTML comment this way
um and you know who knows when this
stuff is going to be useful maybe
there's a scenario and you really need
to comment something out and uh and you
can't do it uh because you know the
stuff is sanitized or maybe like you
can't put a maybe it needs to be like
URL comp oh this is actually a viable
scenario
um like if you have like for some reason
it doesn't want you to have a uh bang in
the URL I've seen that before and uh but
you can have the question mark so that
could be a cool way to smuggle in a HTML
comment without
um without using the Bang Yeah and we
also showed like you know with this
other exercise Vector that just came out
like you can do some weird stuff with an
HTML comment like in the tag as like
part of the idea or part of the
attribute right so you could potentially
combine these all these things together
and chain it into one crazy bug that uh
bypasses a lot of laughs or bypasses you
know everything yeah bypasses everything
yeah yeah even the HTML parser yes yeah
the HTML parser is like what I could
sense uh Dom purify bypass coming it's
it's like right on oh yeah next week or
something funny dude the live overflow
video he he's like ah you know I'm gonna
go straight for the for the super boss
Dom purify right and Dom period I was
like nope nope yeah been there done that
yeah exactly yeah that that piece of
software is pretty freaking solid it
would be it would be really cool to get
a bypass in that though yeah so I don't
know if you saw uh Mr Tux racer he uh he
had tweeted out going on the next thing
uh yeah Mr Trucks racer tweet it out uh
a couple days ago I think he said you
know would there be any interest in a
blog post about patch diffing I've been
doing a lot of patch stiffing lately and
it seems like something that might be an
interesting topic like let me know and
so people replied and said yeah yeah for
sure and yesterday uh he published a
post on his blog rcecurity.com
that goes into how he patchdiffed a CBE
in woocommerce and actually exploited it
on a Target
um and so this I think is a great case
study about sort of how to approach
these types of things patch diffing is
like a great way to find sort of hidden
attack surfaces those like end day one
day two day type vulnerabilities that
exist maybe they've been talked about in
like release notes or something but you
haven't ever seen a public blog
detailing and what the actual
vulnerability is or there's no POC and
again this is like a great way to get
that edge against like the other hackers
especially if you're a full-time hacker
or you're just looking for some new
attack surface keeping your finger on
the pulse like now anytime you see
woocommerce you're gonna be like hang on
a sec there's there's a bug for that
um I'm not sure how exactly he found
initially the like the post I guess
there was just a security advisor he
said he like just mentioned like that
there was this uh there he noticed there
was a an advisory published on word
fence for this uh this bypass and if you
look it up it's got the CV is like a 9.8
critical so I think that would probably
catch most people's attention
woocommerce I think is also pretty
pretty common it's pretty pretty widely
used yeah yeah
um so he went he got the source he
difted against the old version sure
enough figured out how to exploit it and
it's it's crazy it's just like one
header right it's simple dude xwc pay
platform checkout user equals one and uh
with that header you can create new
users and set them as an admin and just
escalate immediately to to Wordpress
account admin it's uh it's super super
wild dude yeah I I've read this blog
post and I was like you know I know that
I know that Julian
um does a decent amount of like
WordPress related stuff which I think is
cool because not a lot of people do
because uh I don't know I I don't I
really honestly don't know why people
don't go after it more core WordPress
core is really solid like if you can buy
a bug in WordPress Court you're pretty
much you know you're set because that's
like 70 on the Internet or whatever but
um the plugins are pretty whack
um and you can enumerate the plugins
um really easily
um
so yeah it's uh there's a lot of scope
there um if you're willing to do some
source code review and this one you can
see just how well this paid off
um yeah just a real I mean and and this
is a good case study as well of like how
patch shipping doesn't have to be super
mega hard like I mean he literally just
dipped it and he was like there's like
three things different about this
specific commit and uh and then you know
he Dives in and it's literally just like
add a header and it just destroys
everything yeah
um yeah I think for me like what a lot
of the reasons why I've like not
exploited something on WordPress there's
like two main reasons one is that it's
really hard to get the plug-in source
code without paying for it or like
doing some jumping through a lot of
Hoops to like get your hands on the
actual plug-in which we've talked about
it like pay for stuff you'll get an
advantage generally speaking but that
can also be risky depending on how how
much the plugin costs the other side of
it is that there's a really common
WordPress plug-in like scanner thing uh
tool I can't I can't remember like yeah
WP scan yep and that generally just
looks for like public vulnerabilities
that are like it are known to be
exploitable and so if it's not showing
up in there then you may not know to
even look for it and you may not dive
any deeper than that you might just see
oh it's got these plugins okay move on
and so going that extra step and getting
your hands on the plug-in code patching
patch stiffing it against a known
vulnerability or something like that
yeah and then exploiting it you know it
it takes a little bit of extra effort
but I think it's generally going to be
worth it yeah so so
I I think that the piece about the
getting your hands on the plug-in code
that can be true if it's a pay-to-play
plug-in but like in my I've actually had
a lot of luck with just going to work
you know wordpress.org plugins and
finding the plugin and then just
pressing the download button downloading
as a zip and you get the source code
right I mean I think I think um I'm not
sure if he did it this way in the actual
yeah it looks like he actually dipped it
inside of like his own local machine or
whatever so you'd you could go and
download the various older versions of
it and then diff it but sometimes they
even have like GitHub repos with the
Full Source in there and various you
know commits and stuff like that which
would make it even much easier so yeah I
appreciate it I think um if anybody
really wants to try to do some
um
source code review related stuff it
would be really cool to kind of go to uh
just go at look at the top WordPress
plugin maybe like scroll down like three
or four pages right like get to get to
the ones that are not like the mega mega
WordPress plugins but like the semi Mega
you know popular WordPress plugins and
then just do a security assessment of
those and if you can pop one that's got
you know like this one has 600 000 plus
active uh installations I'm sure you'll
be able to make some money off of that
on a bug uh you know somewhere in bug
Bounty yeah and I believe specifically
this this was in woocommerce payments
right so yeah so that's where it's like
a little weird right like if you look at
the top commercial plugins on WordPress
the third top commercial plug-in is
woocommerce not woocommerce payments the
woocommerce woocommerce has five million
active installations over 5 million
whereas woocommerce payments is 600 000
plus so it's just like little things
like that right like but I also think
there's probably some really interesting
research
if you were to do a deep Dive Source
Code review on all of those top plugins
in general I am
sure that they're not all up buttoned up
nicely and up to Securities back there's
there's got to be some zero days in
there uh I I I can feel it for sure and
actually that's a really cool pattern
actually Joel that you mentioned is
that's like a a supplemental plug-in to
a mega mega mega popular plug-in right
right so woocommerce is like like you
said top top five you know uh most
popular Koreans yeah top top three
um and and so you know maybe like a a
plug-in that sort of integrates with
that or like you know connects up with
that that that could be a really good
way to find a plug-ins that are a little
bit less security tested but also have a
lot of widespread use right and the same
sort of impact right like if you can
find like escalate from that secondary
plug-in into a main plug-in because it's
used as a dependency
that you know it's not it may not have
the same amount of scrutiny in the same
amount of Security checks and stuff like
you said yeah no that's good stuff man
good good good tips I might actually
check that out myself
um okay two more news today we're almost
through the news in our defense we
haven't done news in a little while
because you know last episode was with
Cosman so
um yeah
oh and then the one before that was with
uh was with rezzo and and Daniel so yeah
yeah dude we haven't done news in a
while okay all right we're just catching
up on some news yeah
um I don't know if we talked about this
dude the CBS S4
yeah I don't know if we did we talk
about it in person
we talked about it in person because uh
RAM sexy yeah uh notice that in the
cbss4 draft they had made some changes I
and I I recall this was while we were in
London and I was like oh that's really
cool like Ram sexy just like tweeted
this out
um so back June 21st Ram sexy uh uh
Pierre Luke uh tweeted out that there
were changes in the cbss4 draft spec
that it said specifically under the
Privileges required section that
self-service provision accounts that may
be necessary to attack a cloud service
do not constitute a privilege
requirement if the attacker can grant
themselves permission these permissions
as part of the attack and this feels
fairly straightforward like this feels
logical like that feels like how it
should be that that feels like it
shouldn't need explanation or need to be
explicitly written but if you look at
how cbss3 is scored that is not the case
uh often times having to create you're
an account does count as privileges
required so like even though you could
just go self-register and give yourself
these perms for some reason in cvss3
it gets graded as oh you need privileges
to do that instead of just being like a
completely unauth like you know which is
like I get it like that's that's the
worst case scenario but when the when
the worst like when when the next step
is having to walk through an open
doorway like that's not I don't really
count that as like having to pick a lock
you know what I mean it's like wow dude
you just you just made like a pretty
good analogy on air on the Fly
like maybe that's my own weakness but
like I just can't do analogies on the
fly like that like you know that gets a
that gets a slow clap for you too thank
you very good thank you thank you thank
you I am half asleep still yeah no I
mean like dude you're killing it today I
mean I couldn't even tell
um but yeah no I I agree and and it's
kind of a shame that CVS S3 and 3.1
didn't address this a little bit earlier
because it would have saved a lot of bug
bounty hunters a lot of money
um but
yeah exactly yeah
um I was glad to see cvss4 did have that
but here's the thing so go to that tweet
click the quotes man
yep a couple days ago yesterday
um somebody somebody tweeted out so
apparently and I actually went and I
checked this because I was like oh maybe
it's just like a bug no indeed they
removed it at least in the current draft
spec for CBS S4 they have removed that
sentence from the Privileges required uh
section it's just it disappeared like a
week after Abraham sexy tweeted that out
and uh
who knows maybe maybe somebody just like
hit the lead on the wrong commit
I don't know I don't know it's uh so I
think it'll be interesting to see what
happens I know a lot of people are
picking them on Twitter being like
what's going on like why did they change
this so I I don't think they've they've
actually said anything yet as to what
the reason was for removing that from
the draft spec but I'm sure that people
will demand some sort of an answer so
it'll be good to see yeah yeah I'd like
to use the the power of the critical
thinking audience real quickly here like
I'm gonna put we're gonna put this tweet
um by Reef BR in the in the description
okay we need to go to this tweet and we
need to tag the freaking
um first first.org you know Twitter
account and be like what the heck is
going on because this is gonna this is
like taking money right out of our
pockets here right and um and yeah I
would really like them to put that
sentence back someone made a joke I
think in the comments that was like this
is this is big bug Bounty lobbying for
like you know changes in this in the
spec
um uh yeah I would really like like an
explanation at least
um about why that decision was made uh
and hopefully we can get it reverted
yeah yeah I'm about I'm actually quote
tweeting them now I'm going what's up
with this at first.org thinking Emoji
yeah we we absolutely need to do that so
we should I think I don't think that
tweet even yeah so Pierre Luke's um
tweet got like a bunch of interaction uh
on it like 230 likes or something like
that and a bunch of retweets and then
this other guy like has only got like 22
likes or whatever and retweets yeah this
is the one that needs to be like smacked
upon you know yeah 100 hopefully uh
hopefully we get some clarification from
first.org soon it's also really funny
because like there are so many familiar
names in the replies on the ram sexy
tweet just like celebrating the change
yeah yeah and I don't I don't know how
many of them have have realized that
they they're getting Bamboozled here so
yeah we need to go into that original
thread and like Ping all the people and
be like look at this look at this yeah
yeah
party man the last final news entry for
today
um is and we saved the best for last not
gonna lie you know a Tom Nom Nom tool
that's like mega bug Bounty news right
there yeah yeah so Tom uh Tom has not
actually been putting out a bunch of
tools lately
um but he drops this one on us which is
which is great uh and I think I think
it's pronounced
Jace sluice JS Luis yeah Jay sluce Chase
loose before this episode I went on
online and like tried to find a video of
someone talking about it so I could like
I don't know I I just I give up so Tom
actually tweeted about like the the way
to um
yeah yeah so let me find the exact tweet
but I freaking love Tom that he would do
yes man so somebody yes so so he tweeted
out like that he had announced a new
tool at b-sides leads in the UK it's
called J sluice um basically what it
does is it takes in like a giant
string of JavaScript and it will parse
it out and it will do a bunch of
heuristics and AST and that kind of
stuff to identify all the URLs and paths
and secrets within it and output that to
you and somebody actually replied and
was like this is awesome but how do I
pronounce the name and so he replied to
J dash sluice
s-o-o-o-s-e-j sluice so I think sluice
is like uh
like a term for something that's loose
is a an act of rinsing or showering with
water I I think I don't know this might
be a UK term or something because uh I
was not familiar with it but yeah he
commented under another one too and he
says it's named after sluicebox a thing
you use to find gold so I guess that's
like the little Sifty thing that you use
yeah yeah when you're panning for gold
yep nice nice cool solid that makes a
lot more sense but yeah so the tool is
really cool
um it it does something which I think
has been needed
um in the industry for a while which is
it helps us to extract URLs from JS
files and there are some really cool
tools out there I think the one I think
link finder is it by
um yeah dude I was trying to remember
what it was because it was actually
crazy timing a couple days before this
came out I was talking with somebody in
person at the at the live hacking event
and I was like yeah isn't there some
tool that like parses the JavaScript and
it pulls out the string constants and
like look looks for URL paths or
something like that and this is
basically exactly that but better yeah
so yeah for some context like for those
who don't know Tom Nom Nom is like an
incredible bug Bounty Hunter
for many many years uh one of the ogs I
would I would consider and uh it a
couple years ago he left and he started
working at Bishop Fox as uh doing select
security tooling and that kind of stuff
yeah and um he's been a little bit quiet
since then I'd imagine just because he's
been uh you know building cool cool
stuff like this right and uh and yeah
here we go this is an awesome awesome
tool to see from Tom num nom awesome to
see that he's still doing you know that
kind of like the security in the book
about any type of stuff and this is
going to be an awesome contribution to
the bug Bounty Community because this is
such an amazing tool that's useful for
parsing the JavaScript instead of having
to like dig through a million lines of
obfuscated minified javascripts you can
just throw through J sluice and see what
it outputs yeah absolutely yeah and so
unlike link finder which is what I had
been currently using up until this point
as well as just my own set of regexes
this actually uses
um go tree sitter which is I guess a
library which allows you to parse sort
of syntaxical grammars a little bit
easier right and um and it uses that in
order to parse out the whole JS file and
do a little bit more intelligent
matching on what sort of
um so what sort of lines or what sort of
variable assignments and stuff like that
are going to be resulting in a URL being
formed and then you know passing that
back to you with a little bit more
information so
um I really like that because it does
take that little bit out that I would
have to do with a different tool of like
going back to finding the JS source code
and then reading it and being like Oh
you know ah it truncated this you know
URL parameter that I really need or
something like that
um and it and it and it kind of makes it
a little bit more cohesive and put
together which is really cool yeah yeah
super cool I mean tomorrow mom is like
an amazing uh I mean his brain is just
like great a great it's like yeah he's
like 5x like what most people are doing
and so it's um I didn't even know what
this this tree sitter was yeah but it's
like uh it's a syntax like tree part
like a generic sort of like tree parsing
tool and then the goat trees tree sitter
is basically goldling bindings on top of
that and there were other language
bindings as well so if you wanted to
write your own version of this in a
different language like rust or
something for example there is a rust
library that binds to tree sitter as
well
um so I think this is uh super awesome
to see this kind of work in the space uh
oftentimes so much of security research
is just like regex instead of actual
parsing and like technical like low
level type stuff so it's really really
cool to see something like this come out
and I think it's a great a great example
case if you want to just like read
through the code and see how it works
about how something like this you might
be able to make a different version of
it or or another version of it yeah for
sure all right man we made it we made it
through the news
um just take a breath
all right donate my brain again yeah
right okay
um so what I was hoping to do today with
the direction for the Pod is just kind
of go through a bunch of client-side
related stuff
um yeah it's all client-side I think
um that people I feel like people should
know about that are kind of at The
Fringe of stuff or or specifically stuff
that I've learned at life hacking events
um just from other like really crazy
good researchers
um so uh let's let's kind of hit this
list the first one actually we talked
about this a little bit before
um personally but uh there's this
function in JavaScript called import
right and this allows you to import
um
well essentially it's a it's a module
import functionality for uh ecmascript
and it it kind of blows the mind how it
actually works in the browser because I
didn't really think that would yeah like
yeah I remember when you first showed me
this and I was like are you sure that
this were like I I had I had you
actually walk me through like showing me
that it was actually functioning in the
browser because I was 100 sure this was
a node.js thing yeah and that this was
not going to be possible and just like
standard JavaScript within the browser
and
it it works I mean it's so weird it's
the
strangest functionality that I've seen
like it's extremely counterintuitive
because you would expect that this type
of stuff just wouldn't exist in standard
JavaScript for security reasons uh and
yet it does yeah I feel like but I
learned about this originally from file
descriptor because whenever like I met
file descriptor at a live hacking event
a long time ago and uh and whenever I
had like a weird JavaScript situation I
would just be like I would just ping him
and we'd get on a call and he'd like
figure it out for me and I was like oh
this is great so I saw him use this once
when we were talking about code golf
right like how to minimize the amount of
code that you have and accomplish a goal
and he used this to like import from an
external you know uh script and I was
like oh this is pretty sick uh yeah and
yeah it saved my butt a couple times
because a lot of times you you know even
if you can get an alert to pop if you
have a um
sort of a length limit on uh your your
input for an xss it's not actually
possible for you to get
um or I guess I won't say it's not
possible let me let me let me retract
that statement because it's been proven
time and time again that you can do a
lot of crazy stuff but
um a lot of times you have to they
you're asked to prove arbitrary
JavaScript execution
um normally by importing a script or or
a show that you can execute long-form
JavaScript for an exploit right
um
and this is a really cool tool for that
um and so yeah I just wanted to make
sure the folks knew about this because I
I think I kind of took this for granted
working with file descriptor and I think
most of the people that I've showed it
to have actually been like wait what
yeah yeah super crazy and also if if you
actually go into the the Mozilla uh docs
the reference talks about this MDM web
web dogs that talk about this there's a
specific warning that they call out that
says warning do not export a function
called then from a module because this
will cause the module to behave
differently when it's imported
dynamically than when it's imported
statically and so I think this is a
really interesting attack scenario where
it's it's a bit of an edge case but if
you're able to do some sort of a file
right or something like that where you
can then get to an import if the code
say you have like some Dynamic import
that's importing from a file that you
can then control but it's calling dot
then on it just like how with
um deserialization bugs where there's
like a function that's going to be
called implicitly just by how how it's
functioning you can hijack that by
defining a then function in your module
that's going to be exported and then
it'll run when it's imported on the site
yeah no that that's that's really cool I
didn't I I didn't see that and scroll
down there to see that so that that's
definitely another interesting attack
Vector
um
but yeah no this is this is really sweet
and it does allow my my access has
payloads to get a little shorter which I
appreciate because it's actually not
very trivial to get xss like for example
if you have if you have an image tag or
an SVG tag
um xss it's not trivial to get a script
imported in that scenario because you
can't just use script Source right
um that doesn't work after the Dom has
already been loaded
um and so yeah this is a cool tool for
getting you there yeah yeah and I think
it still adheres to CSP and stuff right
like there's still yeah it does yeah
there's still like limitations and stuff
that that it's not like just a complete
like bypass of the security features but
it's just another way to basically get
your JavaScript into the page yeah all
right cool
um next one was and this is one we've
talked about before but um Gareth
Hayes's book JavaScript for hackers I I
kind of took a read through it and noted
down some cool sections
um and I'm just gonna was just gonna
shout out a couple of these let me pull
up the book here
um yeah
okay so the first section that I thought
was really interesting was he he talks
about how to
um do how to the various different types
of JS comments that there are and there
are way more than I than I thought that
particularly interesting one was that
sort of a legacy piece from before the
browser is actually used
um before they used JavaScript in all
the browsers use JavaScript there was
sort of a legacy implementation of where
you can use an HTML comment inside of
JavaScript as a comment which I totally
didn't know definitely didn't know about
this and just generally speaking this
book is like an insane resource it's
kind of
the Pinnacle of the kind of stuff that
we're talking about in terms of
documenting Strange Behaviors yeah that
you can that aren't necessarily
vulnerabilities by themselves but you
can often tie these behaviors together
to exploit different scenarios easier or
more effectively and it's twenty dollars
on lean Pub yeah so that's like not even
that's like a fraction of at one xss
that you could definitely get with this
book so uh definitely I would recommend
investing in it and buying it and giving
it a thorough read and take some notes
in your notes.txt file
and uh and definitely take take some
take some learnings from this because
there's so many interesting weird
behaviors that the browser does to
accommodate for like old Legacy old
browsers or Legacy behavior and that
kind of stuff to make stuff work across
like new old stuff work in new browsers
that you can then exploit to your
advantage yeah for sure and and so I'm
gonna I'm gonna tell you scroll to page
66 in the in the um in the book
um and then he also mentions so there's
there's four types of comments he
mentions in here and I'm not gonna you
know I'm not gonna read them all read
them all out because uh you know I want
you guys got to go buy the book but the
the last one there number four in that
list I I couldn't get that one to work
so I thought that one was a little bit
interesting yeah I feel it I'm gonna
double check because that looks like
it's a non-ascii character
it could be I copied it but it I I don't
know I couldn't get it to work but I
will I will tell them about the first
one on the list another
um so I already mentioned that you can
use an HTML comment inside of Js Js but
also there's another comment which is
hashtag bang which I did not know about
um and that only he says the first
example will only work if it's the first
JavaScript state statement if it appears
elsewhere a syntax error will be raised
um and so I I just didn't know about
that and I think that's another really
cool
um Edge case that you can use to to
comment some stuff out in the beginning
of a of a JavaScript block yeah okay so
yes I did check that character it looks
like a like a standard character it's
actually a Unicode character it's the en
dash so on Mac it's like if you do
option that it's like the long like the
long Dash you know what I mean like uh
sometimes I think man yeah like
sometimes if you do a dash dash it'll
get converted into an en dash where it's
like a lot it's like a long Dash It's
really more of a writing formality than
anything yeah um but uh yeah that's
super super interesting again I wonder
if this is like backwards compatibility
type stuff where the two dashes it's
like equivalent to the en dash and then
yeah yeah nice yeah I I think I think
there might be that might have just
gotten extended to a that should might
should have been two dashes because it
that's the end of the oh yeah maybe it's
a typo in the book and we said sorry
Gareth now we're now we're just you know
but yeah apparently you know there's a
way for you to actually comment out a
whole line with the dash with the you
know closing HTML
um comment
um you know but yeah that that seems a
little bit weird I'm gonna have to
assess that out a little bit more I
tried it before I it might have been it
might be something that the browsers
have stopped implementing
um as a as a security measure or not but
um so a couple really cool pieces in
here
um
you know how to do how to smuggle in
JavaScript comments because those can be
useful in JavaScript scenarios where
you're injecting directly into a
JavaScript block and you've got to
comment out the rest of the
um the block yeah a little bit of a side
tangent here uh at The Meta event So
Meta has this thing called Hermes okay
it's it's a JavaScript engine that they
wrote uh and it's super super
interesting it's similar to V8 in in
like what it does but uh there's a whole
community of researchers who only focus
on testing and finding bugs in Hermes
just like how there is V8 as well how
there's like you know Chrome hackers or
whatever like people who find JavaScript
engine bugs and it's the same thing for
Hermes and this type of weird syndax
stuff makes me wonder like where that
parsing is actually happening within a
JavaScript engine yeah and sort of like
how that functionality is working and
whether or not you could actually
pinpoint within the engine these types
of edge cases for how the how the engine
is identifying account comment and like
what qualifies as a comment and then use
that to your advantage to find either
new exploit exploitation cases or other
exploitation cases that may not even be
mentioned here yeah dude I I have
endless respect for those people that
just like pick this one project or like
this one focus and then just like
you know like that's it's it takes so
much dedication and and you know the
knowledge does compound though so it
kind of makes sense why they would want
to keep that snowball rolling of
knowledge yeah for sure and and while
you were talking about that actually did
go back uh and you know I I was not able
to reproduce that before because it got
normalized into the
um the elongated uh Dash like you said
yeah the en dash but actually if you put
two dashes like I think that's what it
should be
um that becomes the closing HTML comment
and that actually does work as a comment
in in JavaScript so okay we might have
to tell Gareth because I want to update
his book he has a little typo in there
from he probably typed it on on a Mac or
something and it yeah it got auto
corrected but you know these are just
the secrets you get for listening to
critical thinking podcast you know even
even Garrett's book we're hacking it
yeah now you know
um all right so next one was okay dude
this one's actually really interesting
um this is another one that I just kind
of took for granted I think just because
of like something I saw early on in my
bug Bounty experience but um this is
regarding a specific context where you
are injecting into oftentimes what it
ends up being is a JavaScript variable
okay so you know you're inside a script
tag you're in a JavaScript variable and
your input is going inside of that
variable right now that variable is
being defined with either single or
double quotes per JavaScript it could be
a templating string as well but that's
rare
um and uh if you're inside that
um you know you the initial Instinct
would be to try to use double quotes or
single quotes to escape that variable
and get an xss you know just by
injecting JavaScript in there
um and then you know the second sort of
Route if that fails would be to try to
do something funky with like backslashes
right and escaping you know the end of
that um that double quote or the single
quote and seeing if you can link it
together with another injection point to
kind of get an xss
um but another one that I feel like
people miss a decent bit is you have to
still sanitize the HTML elements because
yeah um because you know at the end of
the day you're in inside of a script tag
and the only way that the browser is
going to know that that script tag is
going to end is like with an actual you
know back you know less than slash
script you know end tag and so if you do
that inside of the JavaScript context
you it's going to just cut off the rest
of the JavaScript and then you have HTML
injection and you can get xss from there
so yeah I mean there's nothing in the
browser spec or anywhere that states
that you have to have valid JavaScript
in your script tags right like you can
have like an open quote that never ends
right and then you just close it with a
script tag right and so in that same
sense like if you have something that's
being injected directly into a string
you don't have to end that string you
could just close the script tag and keep
like put elements in the page yeah yeah
and then you know get xss file like you
know and and on click or an on Hover
right an online event handler which is
going to have a different CSP as well
because the CSP for script source is not
the same as you know like
including other for example an import
right like that's going to go to a
different csb yeah that is a little bit
tricky though if you have a non-spaced
uh script tag and that that script has a
nonce on it right if you close off that
stick tag then you're not going to be
able to smuggle your your you know
payload inside of that scripted nonce so
csb it's kind of a it's kind of a
double-edged sword sometimes with that
sort of thing yeah yeah I wonder maybe
that could that that's something that we
could talk about in the future is uh
there's the CSP evaluator tool that that
Google made that's and that's pretty
good
um you can basically just paste the CSP
in there we'll link it but you just
paste like a CSP direct uh full like
directive in there it'll tell you like
if it's vulnerable to things they have a
list of known uh domains and like paths
that have
um
what is it the like JS uh
the callbacks basically the Json
endpoints
I'm not I'm not sure what you're talking
about yeah so Google has the the CSP uh
evaluator cfp evaluator dot with Google
right and if you put a whole content
security policy string in there it will
check it and it'll tell you whether or
not each part of it is safe and whether
or not there are certain bypasses so
certain domains like youtube.com and
stuff they have
um
alert like poppable basically like
gadgets that you can exploit that still
will
uh they'll still adhere to the CSP yeah
you can use them to get an xss
and I'm wondering if there's anything
that goes beyond that that does more of
a deep dive in terms of like
uh not necessarily a problem with the
CSP but ways that you could work within
the CSP outside of like
you know just oh this domain you could
use this domain as a gadget to then pop
an exercise maybe you could all you
could also say oh you would have to put
something within a script tag in order
to adhere to this nonce that's in the
csb or something like that yeah dude and
I don't think I've seen any tool like
that CSP is like a whole episode of It's
episode probably actually originally had
it in this episode to talk about some
stuff about CSP and cores and I was like
uh you know especially after all the
news we added there's just no way we're
going to get to any of that today yeah
uh yeah so yeah and for what it's worth
the CSP evaluator is based on Research
that was done in 2016. so it's been
almost oh my God it's getting we're
getting old dude it's been almost 10
years oh my gosh
so dude you know there's there's
definitely been some bypasses and stuff
that are not going to be in that list
um and some other like confounding
factors that are there that are not
going to be in that list yeah that are
worth looking at so I don't think the
CSP value evaluator is the sort of
end-all be-all uh when you're looking at
a CSP and there are going to be some
other sort of knowledge things that
you're going to want to keep in mind
when you're looking at a CSP that won't
get called out by the evaluator yeah
yeah for sure and it like I feel like
those endpoints though like you were
saying before the Json PM points in
particular like I've thought about
reporting endpoints where you can like
for example you can smuggle in a um a
semicolon or like a comma or something
that will allow you to actually inject
um uh arbitrary.js code into the
Callback parameter for those Json P
endpoints and I totally feel like that's
a bug especially for big companies where
it's like you know you're gonna you're
going to have other people approving
your site as a as a CSP you know bypass
right as a as a as an allowed site
within CSP like you've got to use that
that power responsibly
um right and you know make sure you're
taking care of those um those Json P
endpoints and there's just there's just
a you know a lot like you mentioned
there's a lot of gadgets out there
that'll still allow you to just bypass
it unfortunately and again I think this
is one of those those artifacts of like
Legacy support where they're now in a
place where if they were to change how
that endpoint works for like a Json PE
endpoint then stuff that's using it in
the past may break because they're using
it incorrectly and and so now it's like
vulnerable by Design but they can't fix
it yeah because they can't migrate
people away from it because it's like
hard-coded yeah using a semicolon in
their Json you know like nobody I've
seen a lot of really sketchy a lot of
really sketchy engineer behaviors
if they engineered it like that their
site deserves to break you know okay
yeah it deserves to be a Json point at
that point exactly
um okay the last thing I want to talk
about from
from Garrett's book
um is his notes on Prototype uh
pollution
um which I feel like was sort of a
a bug that I just kind of thought was
like
researchy you know like man it's
everywhere I've seen it I've seen it in
like one life hacking event someone got
like a crazy bug with it
um but another one you're talking about
yeah and and I'm not gonna go down the
the rabbit hole too much of like trying
to explain all of this on the Pod today
but um the section of this book was
really interesting to me and actually
helped me understand prototype pollution
a lot more and actually gave me some
good Hands-On tips for scanning for it
and for how to identify it within a you
know an organization or within an
application
um
and so I feel like this is one of the
things where it would be a lot of work
because they're kind of hard to exploit
even once you find them but this could
be something where you could set up a
headless browser you could put this sort
of payload in the URL that he mentions
in the in the book and then
um you know spam that across all of the
websites and all of the endpoints that
you know about
um you know through Recon and uh and I
think that would probably kick out some
pretty quality results yeah and for what
it's worth in in addition Gareth works
at portswiger
um but
the portswiger Web Academy web Security
Academy has an awesome section it's all
about prototype pollution it goes into
um both the like server side and the
client side aspects of like identifying
what it is how it works
um just like all the intricacies of like
what prototype pollution is and and
what's going on underneath when you're
when you're sending like an underscore
underscore Proto underscore underscore
in your payloads and I would encourage
you to just read about it because it's
definitely one of those things that
doesn't get looked at as much as it
should and if you think about or use
just read just read some developer code
and you'll realize how many places it's
possible to get prototype pollution just
by writing JavaScript you don't have to
be using like low Dash and stuff to get
prototype pollution it definitely exists
in normal developer patterns
um and I think it's a lot more common
than people think
it's just another one of those things
that kind of like an xss you need to
kind of like spray it and see if it's
going to pop anything kind of weird and
it'll be pretty noticeable if it's if
it's behaving with prototype pollution
um sort of sort of behavior there'll be
indicators for sure yeah and and the
server side stuff as well like with node
that's really interesting as well I'm
sure that's a lot you know trickier to
actually exploit because you don't have
the the source code but I I've seen at
least one server-side prototype
pollution that just like yes is amazing
yes in my own job experience I've seen
one not in my current company but uh but
at a previous place I've seen a really
bad server-side prototype pollution and
it was like a systemic uh problem
because it was like a a common pattern
that was being used in like a lot of
different places and it was just like uh
honestly just like a a pitfall that the
engineers thought that this was going to
be fine but it it wasn't and the the
thing with prototype pollution right
especially on the server side is that
you're you're polluting object itself
right so that means that every single
object from then on is going to be
tainted which means that it has way
widespread implications in terms of like
how it can be exported and the things
that it can do and it'll affect all
parts of the application not just one
part of the application and so the
impact can be insane if you get a
server-side prototype pollution yeah and
and I imagine that could even cause dos
as well depending on how the the server
side deals with all of those you know
objects that are sort of corrupted via
the by corrupting the Prototype so
really cool stuff there
um let's since we just mentioned
portswiger Academy let's jump down to
the Dom clobbering uh section this is
another really cool interesting sort of
Fringe bug type that I really actually I
was gonna talk to you guys you know talk
to you guys about it on the Pod and then
I was like oh wait actually like I feel
like I don't actually fully understand
how this gets exploited exploited and
like I clicked on the portsmaker academy
link for this which we'll we'll put in
the description and there's just a
beautiful example Joel look at this code
I don't know if you got a chance to
review this but look at this code like I
totally did not see the way that you
could exploit this
um
and so essentially what they've got
going on here is that they're accessing
an arbitrary you know window object so
window.sum object and they're accessing
an attribute of that object some
object.url and they're setting that as
the source for uh for a script tag right
it actually doesn't seem like that far
out there of a uh of a of a code pattern
right and it's saying if with just HTML
injection Above This above this script
you can hijack this in and get xss on
the page and it does this via injecting
a two a tags
um one that has the IDS some object and
another one that has the ID sub object
and then but the second one also has the
name URL and an href and what ends up
happening here I did break it down in my
browser
um when the the a those two a objects
both have the same ID they get sort of
clustered into
um a Dom collection and that Dom
collection uh allows you to when you
when they add try to access it via
window dot some object that some object
ID the ID for that Dom collection gets
put into that you know window it gets
defined at the window level within the
application so now you've kind of
snagged access to that variable and then
the piece that I didn't know about is
you could Define sub attributes for that
object
yeah I knew you could you know hijack
essentially a variable in the window
with dom clobbering that's like
traditional Dom clobbering that I would
think about
um but then you not only can you do that
but you can also add snag sub attributes
of that
um using this using the the Dom
collection and then the name attribute
inside the second element and then so it
then selects that second a tag right
um when when you use some object.url and
then it abuses the a tags dot tostring
when when you do two string on an a tag
it takes the eight it Returns the href
yeah yeah exactly I mean it's like
amazing again these are like the the
like the edge case like weird stuff that
you kind of
wouldn't necessarily know about or even
expect right like the fact that you can
access any element by its ID off the
window object yeah is like already
uncommon like just like it's super
counter-intuitive behavior that that
would be a thing because it seems fairly
arbitrary that just like defining an ID
would make it accessible on the window
normally you'd expect to have to do like
document.query selector or something
like that and the fact that it just
implicitly does that
already opens up a lot of Windows for
opportunity for exploitation that you
may not have expected originally where
you you can now oh if I can just insert
an HDM element or if I can put something
you know you in the URL on an HTML
element that I don't neces I can't
escape out of it but I can control
what's in the href value or something
right well now you can exploit that
potentially depending on how it's being
used and those types of edge cases are
really important to know yeah it's just
it's just amazing to me how they
combined the the two string you know
manipulation the Dom collection thing
with when you have multiple IDs um with
the same or multiple tags with the same
ID and then this whole weird window
window dot whatever the ID is
functionality here to actually trigger a
a very exploitable scenario in Dom
clobbering I kind of thought dab
clombering was like mostly used for like
sandbox escapes and like weird stuff
like that
um but yeah it actually seems like it
has some very real excess uh
implementations
yeah super super strange Behavior
alrighty man we are at
I guess an hour 17 here oh man where do
we where do we want to go because we got
a bunch of stuff left we have to talk
about but we could push some of this to
the to a different episode yeah
um
do you want to let
I'll leave it up to you I think we could
talk about these last couple things The
Meta tags and stuff or we can we can
save it for another episode you are
start looking like you're you're going
downhill just a little bit um I started
out strong my jet fuel's running out
yeah yeah so let's let's we'll we'll hit
the meta and base tags and then we'll
we'll call it a wrap for this time
around and maybe we'll do another
episode on like weird browser quirks
because there's a lot of other stuff
that we had in the dock here that I
think the people need to know about
um but yeah so the other thing that I
kind of want to mention and this was
actually sparked by a bug at a live
hacking event which you probably know
the one that I'm talking about
um but uh a friend of ours uh used a
meta tag to get a really really crazy
bug at a live hacking event um because
he had an HTML injection
um
and uh and so this is something that I
just kind of wanted to make sure
everyone was aware of because whenever
you have HTML injection it feels kind of
bad you know if you can't get it to to
xss but depending on the context there's
still a lot you can do
um and meta and base tags are two of the
primary tags that you can use to to
really do something cool with
yeah
um I mean this cheat sheet is awesome
there's a ton of cheat sheets out there
but I think
you know uh keep some of your own notes
I think is like the the key I would say
because like otherwise you're gonna have
a folder that's got 50 different cheat
sheets that are bookmarked in it and
when you're trying to think of that one
thing you're gonna have to click through
all of them to find them
um yeah but yeah this is really really
interesting I didn't actually
um I don't really fiddle with meta tags
very much and I think it's kind of
underrated I like early on like way back
in the day like meta tags used to be
like a much easier exploit scenario
where you can just like set like base
URLs or something like that that would
allow you to exploit them I don't know
how much that's still possible yeah so
some of the functionality because you
used to be able to I think trigger xss
via um via a meta tag and right um
according to this cheat sheet it's still
possible using a data URI this was not
something I got to test before
um the episode it says here that it only
works in Safari so I can't test it right
now Joel if you I don't know if you
second most popular browser yeah exactly
seriously if you've got your you know I
don't know if you're on your Mac right
now but if you want to just throw that
little
um you know data scheme into the in to
Safari and see if it works then go for
it but
um but meta essentially has a bunch of
functionality and one of the cool
attributes of it is this HTTP equiv
attribute and originally it was designed
to allow you to essentially set HTTP
headers inside of the the page
like sort of I guess sort of
retroactively because it's like you've
already loaded the body of the request
um and I feel like there's a lot more
potential for that
um you know then then is possible right
now but um if you if you look at this
let's see if I can pull up this picture
that I had in the in the dock the
current values that are accessible for
that are content security policy content
type default style and refresh and each
one of those are all like pretty
freaking interesting I think
um because with content security policy
you can trigger a Content security
policy to execute
um inside the browser using using that
meta tag we see that pretty often that's
that's pretty common
um
but setting the content type this
includes encoding that that's another
thing that I hadn't really thought about
before researching for this episode is
like you may be able to use the meta tag
to change the encoding for the content
body and Trigger some xss further down
in the page
um if you've got some weird injection
points so that's one that's not about
yeah so I just tested this on on Safari
um let's see what version the latest
Ferrari version 16.5.1 and
what it does it throws an error so I
don't know if it's actually exploitable
or maybe you might need to do some
modifications but it does say not
allowed to navigate top frame to data
URL data colon text HTML so it does like
it's parsing it and it's like skipping
over that zero uh zero semicolon thing
yeah uh and it does seem to like try to
do it but maybe this is something that
they added recently
um as as a fix
um because I know that like some of the
things that are in this cheat sheet are
definitely for older versions like it
talks about like Chrome 65 which is
probably it's way out there five five
plus years old yeah yeah for sure and
and so like it said there used to be a
set cookie instruction which is like oh
my gosh that would be lit like nowadays
but the way that I see Meta tags used
most most um commonly now for
exploitation purposes is for this
content security policy stuff and then
also primarily for this redirection
um piece right because like think about
it it's very hard to get actually I
can't even really think of another way
to X to redirect a page with no user
interaction with with just HTML without
using JavaScript right yeah and for what
it's worth that's that works on Safari
at least I just tested that like the
meta redirect for the language tag like
that works totally fine yeah but
redirecting it to a data URL it doesn't
want to do yeah so you've definitely got
that in your pocket and this can be
useful in a bunch of different scenarios
um it can be useful on embedded devices
it can be useful
um in inside of headless browsers
um and so uh the open redirect piece you
know by The Meta tag is really cool and
I would love to see some research
surrounding
um the content type piece because I feel
like there's definitely some interesting
functionality there I was trying to
think about the default style piece
um I I couldn't really come up with
anything but it seems weird to me so
yeah so I mean there's always the the
scenario that always comes to mind with
like style stuff for me is the key like
the key press uh like sniffing where I I
think that's always been like a really
solid attack scenario where if you can
eject Styles like you can either you can
create a really plausible phishing
scenario because you're on an SSL signed
website that's looks completely
different and might have different
different content and stuff but you can
also do like key like key input like
changes where you like hit a background
like a background URL or something and I
think it still goes through some sort of
CSP right
um but you know depending on the
scenario you can sniff keybinds within
the website purely through CSS which is
just like
insane yeah I love I love that bug so
much there's been some really cool stuff
with that and I'm actually I'm looking
at because like w3schools is a great
resource and I use them all the time for
yeah for for you know this sort of thing
but oh yeah there's also well I'm not
I'm just thinking about it freaking out
oh okay oh
geez good can you hear me yeah I'm back
sorry it like it totally went crazy for
just a second okay cool
um yeah so
I I was just thinking about this right
now like as we were talking about CSS a
couple years ago there was a pro a
project that came out called Doom Nukem
CSS and it's a full implementation of
Doom that's written
in HTML and CSS no way and maybe it uses
typescript too I don't actually
I don't actually know but I'm pretty I'm
if I recall correctly I could have sworn
it was like all CSS which is like the
craziest thing but it looks like there's
a decent amount of typescript in here I
might be wrong well you know Gareth
Hayes you know we mentioned him a couple
times on this
um on this episode his personal website
if you go to his Twitter profile and you
click his bio link that's like a CSS
based like freaking interactive game
Masterpiece of a website and it's just
kind of like an ongoing project for him
and I'm like wow that's like such a cool
hobbyist activity of like just mastering
CSS stuff and he and he tweets about
like CSS related quirks all the time
which I think is really helpful as well
yeah what is it Gareth Hayes dot Co dot
UK yeah check it out yeah oh man while
you're checking out no this is exactly
what I was thinking of actually yeah
yeah and so there's some really crazy
stuff you can do with CSS um with just
pure CSS which is nuts but um I was what
I was going to say before my computer
started losing its mind
um was that I went to schools and I was
it says that there's only four
attributes that can go inside of or
values they can go inside of the HTTP
equiv
header or mean html attribute
um but actually I'm looking at some
other stuff and I think there's more so
like I've seen other references to
window.target and content encoding as
well so I'm actually after this episode
I'm gonna go try to suss that out
because I think there might be some
other things we can put in HTTP quiv
that could really really mess with the
you know the Dom that's being loaded up
so definitely some cool stuff I also
wonder if there's like undocumented
features instead like functionality
because I feel like a lot of browsers
will create just like they'll create
weird edge cases with like that they use
internally
um that are only really designed to be
used by them that may not adhere
directly to the HTML spec or what the
public spec says should be possible but
is actually still possible and you know
it's important to remember that just
because the spec says that it should be
this way doesn't mean that it's actually
implemented that way
for sure yeah yeah there's definitely
some some I'm looking through it right
now there's some weird some weird stuff
there so I'm going to check that out
afterwards
um but for for those of you listening
right now what we can what we can
confirm right here is it is helpful for
exploitation in a Content security
policy scenario if you want to make the
content security policy stricter to lock
out like for example a um
like for example if they're loading up a
JS library that does purification or
something like that
then it's helpful there
and then it's also possible to use it
for a no additional click redirect if
you have an HTML injection so that's
helpful as well yeah yeah super cool
um so the other thing that we're going
to talk about here was the base tags
um and base tags this is something that
that I didn't know about until recently
I think these have to be in inside the
head
um uh sort of section within the browser
um or within the Dom so I'm not sure how
often we're getting injections up in
there
um but yeah there's some really cool
stuff you can do with this essentially
it allows you to turn relative URLs into
uh you know fully qualified URLs with
your domain which is super helpful for
um you know hijacking stuff further down
in the flow of the page uh and and maybe
even bypassing CSP in some scenarios
um
I don't know if you can nonce an
external import but um yeah that would
be that would be helpful in that
scenario yeah I'm just testing this one
on Safari as well just to double check
because I'm pretty sure you're right
that it has to be almost certain it has
to be in the in the head yeah yeah I
think I think it has to be
um uh but yeah I I didn't know about
this and this is just another really
cool piece that you can you can use in a
HTML projection it doesn't it doesn't
have to be in the head
maybe Safari's doing something weird uh
yeah this could be something doing weird
but I did just double check and in my
body element I put a bass href and a
script tag and it is trying to load it
from the base Euro wow that's in the
body tag I stand corrected man yeah this
has a lot of power this element
um and HTML like we mentioned HTML
injections can be kind of tricky but
this is definitely something that you
can use to kind of try to turn the tides
in your favor
headers the chromosuna too I've nerd
sniped Joel is just like staring
wide-eyed at his at his computer right
now like no Chrome does it too so yeah
if you put the base tag in maybe yeah
dude I I could have sworn that it was a
head only thing yeah
but okay yeah so a base uh bass tag
anywhere
um will change where it tries to load
from even if it's in the body
very solid man yeah I think that's all
I've got for bass bass stuff
um dude we skipped over so much
second episode with the content that we
didn't even talk about we've already
prepped for another episode I'm just
going to copy this over into the other
dock because this is yeah a lot of stuff
but anything else you want to add before
we wrap this one up uh no I think that
was it I love how this is like one of
our longest episodes and it was like on
a on a U.S holiday and after you Dro you
know just flew back from Korea
yeah yeah another another banger but
yeah no thank you for uh putting
together all these links because there's
no way I would have been able to find
all this stuff and um I've got some
notes I need to take now I think uh
personal stuff I'm just gonna say good
luck to our producer trying to fit all
this in the episode description but
there's like 50 bajillion links but all
right cool that's a wrap awesome all
right yeah catch you later sweet peace
so we we after the episode ended we just
went and kind of tried to suss out that
bass thing a little bit more about the
uh you know being able to put the bass
tag in the body and I swear that was not
something that used to be the case yeah
but it says specifically in the HTML
spec that it has to be in the head head
tag inside the head tag and it works
perfectly fine in the body tag in lots
of browsers so I I've never seen this
documented before and I think this has
some pretty bad exercise implications
yeah I mean uh we're looking at the HTML
spec directly and it says that the
context in which a base element can be
used is within a head element containing
no other base elements and if you put a
base element in a body it works it still
works uh the only real caveat that I've
seen through the limited testing that we
just did is that if there's a base
element in the head already the one in
the body will not override it which is
expected but it shouldn't be possible
that you put one in the body and it
works it should completely ignore it
unless it's in the head uh which is
super wild because you can inject those
so yeah yeah we got to do more live
testing on the Pod
[__] like this all right cool all right
that's a wrap yeah yeah catch it all
right catch you the next week
already after that data packed episode I
have one measly request for you at the
end of this episode and that is for you
to head over to
ctbb.show And subscribe to our
newsletter we're trying to grow the
content over there Jesse Rivera is
putting out some awesome blogcast
summaries of the episodes you don't want
to miss out on those
um so yeah ctpb.show head over there
subscribe thanks
foreign